JOE **KENNERLY**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- joseph.kennerly@gmail.com
- joekennerly.github.io
- github.com/joekennerly
- Inkedin.com/in/joekennerly
- **** 770 855 0229

ABOUT

Self-Motivated software developer experience with team leadership, managing schedules and planning strategies to achieve steps towards objectives that businesses can utilize. The creative process of deconstructing ideas, learning how they work, and reconstructing them to make new representations of the same idea have been the main tools used in developing personal methods to learn and solve problems.

PROJECTS

KTER

github.com/joekennerly/kterapi github.com/joekennerly/kterclient

An event management service focused on saving catering businesses time and money. Built with Django Rest Framework, React, Material UI, and Moment JS.

Balance

balance-react.herokuapp.com github.com/joekennerly/Balance

Personal budgeting application build with React, Semantic UI, and Chart is to depict the difference between the sum totals of two categories, incomes and budgets.

TECH

- Python
- HTML
- Diango
- CSS
- Javascript
- SQL
- React

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

May - Nov 2019

Full stack Software Development

Middle Tennessee State University

Aug 2007 - May 2011

Bachelors in Recording Industry

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

May - November 2019

Full time, immersive software development boot camp practicing full stack programming languages including Javascript / React for front-end, and Python / Django / SQL for back-end development.

- Debugged and refactored existing code bases with a group to practice grooming issue tickets and creating our own prescriptive strategies with the help of daily stand-ups and project retrospectives.
- Utilized entity relationship diagrams to understand data dependencies, and keep code bases consistent.
- Practiced version control with Git and GitHub.
- Interacted with databases using SQL queries.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mellow Mushroom

June 2014 - May 2019

Kitchen Manager, Line Cook

Software Developer

- High-pace environment with emphasis on delivering high quality products within a time-efficient manner.
- Worked closely with the General Manager and Marketing Manager to plan the logistics of the Number One catering department of any Mellow franchise in the country.
- On-site training for kitchen staff based on corporate-approved methods, as well as any other context that may aide the kitchen staff in understanding the products being made.
- Set the schedule for kitchen staff based on times of high volume for the restaurant and prior arrangements set by catering.

Freelance Musician

Audio Engineer, Band member, Drummer

May 2011 - June 2014

- Represented ideas with the use of MIDI sequencing and production with digital audio workstations.
- Managed signal-flow using modular based FM synthesizers.
- Communicated with band members about rehearsal times, developing objectives and metrics of success which would allow easy public exposure for self made products.

Inciite Media

Front End Web Developer

June 2011 - April 2012

- Developed email templates with HTML and CSS.
- Installed a Wordpress site using FTP.

Universal Music Group

Intern

January - May 2011

- Worked with the web department designing and creating static email templates and pages for electronic press kits in video format.
- Emphasized researching the User Interfaces and Experiences of the websites belonging to artists in the UMG catalog and reporting any bugs or points of interest.

Brite Revolution

Intern

June - August 2010

- Worked with a team of interns to come up with a marketing strategy that targets users on Twitter, and draw users to a central platform where they could be exposed to other artists on the platform.
- Developed an automation method using Applescipt to tweet links to selected users stored on an spreadsheet.